Marion Nestle Papers, 1970-2017 MSS.159
Fales Library and Special Collections
- Series IX: Photographs
  This series includes various photographs from Marion Nestle's professional life. It is comprised of head shots as well as photographs from the Surgeon General's Report event in July 1988, a Proctor & Gamble Press Conference in October 1988, Mexico City in 1997, a photo shoot with Claudia Schiffer for Self Magazine in February 1999, "Career Day" events from Spring 1995 and November 1996, construction of the kitchen at the Education Building on 35 W. 4th Street, and a graduation party from May 1998. The series also contains the negatives of some of these photographs as well as negatives from photographs not included in the series.
  - Photo Binder A, July 1988-1999 (Binder A)
  - Photo Binder B, 1995-1997 (Binder B)
  - Photo Binder C, 1998-2010 (Binder C)
- Series X: Printed Material
  Series X: Printed Materials consists of annual reports, catalogues, programs, professional handbooks, newsletters, postcards, marketing packages, magazines and annotated books. Included in this series are research materials that were not clearly identified with any of her books. Periodicals and USDA Publications have been identified as separate subseries and are described further below.
  - Subseries A: USDA Publications
    Subseries A: USDA Publications contains a complete edition of the United States Department of Agriculture's Composition of Foods. A few other smaller USDA Publications are also included.
    - Nutritive Value of Foods Home and Garden Bulletin No. 72 (USDA), 1964; 1971 (Box 88, Folder 1)
    - Composition of Foods: Agriculture Handbook No. 8 Agricultural Research Service (USDA), 1975 (Box 88, Folder 2)
    - Nutritive Value of American Foods Agriculture Handbook No. 465 Agricultural Research Service (USDA), 1975 (Box 88, Folder 3)
    - Composition of Foods: Dairy and Eggs Agriculture Handbook No. 8-1 (USDA), 1976 (Box 88, Folder 4)
    - Composition of Foods: Spices and Herbs Agriculture Handbook No. 8-2 (USDA), 1977 (Box 88, Folder 5)
    - Nutritive Value of Foods (USDA), 1977 (Box 88, Folder 6)
    - Composition of Foods: Baby Foods Agriculture Handbook No. 8-3 (USDA), 1978 (Box 89, Folder 1)
    - Nutritive Value of Foods (USDA), 1978 (Box 89, Folder 2)
    - Composition of Foods: Fats and Oils Agriculture Handbook No. 8-4 (USDA), 1979 (Box 89, Folder 3)
    - Composition of Foods: Poultry Products Agriculture Handbook No. 8-5 (USDA), 1979 (Box 89, Folder 4)
    - Composition of Foods: Soups, Sauces, and Gravies Agriculture Handbook No. 8-6 (USDA), 1980 (Box 90, Folder 1)
    - Composition of Foods: Sausages and Luncheon Meats Agriculture Handbook No. 8-7 (USDA), 1980 (Box 90, Folder 2)
    - Composition of Foods: Breakfast Cereals Agriculture Handbook No. 8-8 (USDA), 1982 (Box 90, Folder 3)
    - Composition of Foods: Fruits and Fruit Jucies Argiculture Handbook 8-9 (USDA), 1982 (Box 90, Folder 4)
    - Composition of Foods: Pork Products Agriculture Handbook 8-10, 1983 (Box 90, Folder 5)
    - Composition of Foods: Vegetables and Vegetable Products Agriculture Handbook 8-11, 1984 (Box 91, Folder 1)
    - Composition of Foods: Nuts and Seed Products Agriculture Handbook 8-12, 1984 (Box 91, Folder 2)
    - Composition of Foods: Beef Products Agriculture Handbook 8-13, 1984 (Box 91, Folder 3)
    - Composition of Foods: Beverages Agriculture Handbook 8-14, 1986 (Box 91, Folder 4)
    - Composition of Foods: Legumes and Legume Products Agriculture Handbook 8-16, 1986 (Box 91, Folder 5)
    - Composition of Foods: Finfish and Shellfish Products Agriculture Handbook 8-15, 1987 (Box 92, Folder 1)
    - Composition of Foods: Fast Foods Agriculture Handbook 8-21, 1988 (Box 92, Folder 2)
    - Composition of Foods: Cereal Grains and Pasta Agriculture Handbook 8-20, 1989 (Box 92, Folder 3)
    - Composition of Foods: Lamb, Veal, and Game Products Agriculture Handbook 8-17, 1989 (Box 92, Folder 4)
    - Composition of Foods: Snacks and Sweets Agriculture Handbook 8-19, 1991 (Box 92, Folder 5)
    - Composition of Foods: Agriculture Handbook No. 8, 1992 (Box 93, Folder 1)
    - Composition of Foods: Baked Products Agriculture Handbook 8-18, 1992 (Box 93, Folder 2)
    - Composition of Foods: Pork Products Agriculture Handbook No. 8-10, 1992 (Box 93, Folder 3)
  - Subseries B: Books and Periodicals
    - Alimentum, 2006 (Box 93, Folder 4)
    - Alimentum, Summer 2007; Winter 2008 (Box 93, Folder 5)
    - Alimentum, Summer 2008 (Box 93, Folder 6)
    - The Art of Eating, 2003 (Box 94, Folder 1)
    - The Art of Eating, 2004; 2006-2007 (Box 94, Folder 2)
    - Authentic Mexican: Regional Cooking from the Heart of Mexico by Rick Bayless, 1987 (Box 94, Folder 3)
    - Beard House The Magazine of the James Beard Foundation, Summer/Fall 1998 (Box 94, Folder 4)
    - Bija: The Seed, Winter 2008 (Box 94, Folder 5)
    - Bon Appétit, January 2005; May 2005; November 2005 (Box 94, Folder 6)
    - The Creative Cook's Walnut Journal, Holiday 1985 (Box 94, Folder 7)
    - Eating Well, Summer 2002; October 2009 (Box 94, Folder 8)
    - Edible Brooklyn, Fall 2009 (Box 94, Folder 9)
    - Edible East End, Winter 2005; Summer 2009 (Box 94, Folder 10)
    - Edible Finger Lakes, Winter 2008 (Box 94, Folder 11)
    - Edible Manhattan, Sept/Oct 2008; Nov/Dec 2008; Mar/Apr 2009 (Box 95, Folder 1)
    - Edible Manhattan, Sept/Oct 2009 (Box 95, Folder 2)
    - Food & Foodways, April-June 2009 (Box 95, Folder 3)
    - Food, Culture, & Society, Fall 2007; March 2008 (Box 95, Folder 4)
    - Food, Culture, & Society, June 2008; September 2008 (Box 95, Folder 5)
    - Gastronomica, Winter 2009; Spring 2009 (Box 95, Folder 6)
    - International Association of Culinary Professionals: The Fashion of Food, March-April 2012 (Box 95, Folder 7)
    - New York's Master Chefs and Old Fashioned Desserts by Richard Sax, 1983; 1985 (Box 95, Folder 8)
    - Restaurant Business, June 2002 (Box 95, Folder 9)
    - [Japanese Language Edition] Safe Food, 2009 (Box 96, Folder 1)
    - Salute to American Food, undated (Box 96, Folder 2)
    - Spain Gourmetour, May-Aug 2008; Sept-Dec 2008 (Box 96, Folder 3)
    - Spain Gourmetour NYT Supplement, Fall 2008 (Box 96, Folder 4)
    - Spain Gourmetour, Jan-Apr 2009; May-Aug 2009 (Box 96, Folder 5)
    - Time, June 2004 (Box 96, Folder 6)
    - University of California: Public Health Berkeley, Spring 2004 (Box 96, Folder 7)
    - Waitrose Entertaining, Spring/Summer 2009 (Box 96, Folder 8)
  - Subseries C: General Printed Material
    - Shirley Temple Quaker Oats Advertisement from Good Housekeeping, 1937 (Box 96, Folder 9)
    - The Story of Semi-Sweet Chocolate and Its Uses, 1941 (Box 96, Folder 10)
    - American Legion, 1969 (Box 96, Folder 11)
    - Alaskan Recipes Cards, 1984 (Box 96, Folder 12)
    - The American Journal of Clinical Nutrition, 1988; 1994 (Box 97, Folder 1)
    - The American Journal of Clinical Nutrition, 1999; 2003 (Box 97, Folder 2)
    - American Institute of Food and Wine [AIFW], 1990-1998; [undated] (Box 97, Folder 3)
    - The Nation's Investment in Children, 1991 (Box 97, Folder 4)
    - Building Human Capital: The Impact of Post-Secondary Education on AFDC Recipients in Five Stars, September 1993 (Box 97, Folder 5)
    - Clippings for Somalia Food Aid Paper, 1992-1993 (Box 97, Folder 6)
    - Clippings for Somalia Food Aid Paper, 1993 (Box 97, Folder 7)
    - Clippings for Somalia Food Aid Paper, 1993-1994 (Box 97, Folder 8)
    - The Museum of Modern Art Appointment Calendar, 1995 (Box 97, Folder 9)
    - [Printed Material: General], 2000-2005 (Box 98, Folder 1)
    - Modernizing America's Food and Farm Policy: Vision for a New Direction Report of the Agriculture Task Force, 2006 (Box 98, Folder 2)
    - [Printed Material: General], 2006-2007 (Box 98, Folder 3)
    - The Snail Newsltter, Winter 2007; Summer 2009; Winter 2008; Spring 2009 (Box 98, Folder 4)
    - Italy and the Mediterranean Diet Food Culture, Nutrition, and the Question of Quality, 2007 (Box 98, Folder 5)
    - [Printed Material: General], 2007 (Box 98, Folder 6)
    - Fighting Junk Food Marketing to Kids a Toolkit for Advocates, 2007 (Box 99, Folder 1)
    - [Printed Materal: General], 2007 (Box 99, Folder 2)
    - [Printed Materal: General], 2008; [undated] (Box 99, Folder 3)
    - Norman E. Bourlag International Symposium Confronting Crisis: Agriculture and Global Development in the Next Fifty Years, October 15-17, 2008 (Box 99, Folder 4)
    - Les Dames d'Escoffier International Membership Directory, 2008 (Box 99, Folder 5)
    - [Printed Material: General], 2008 (Box 99, Folder 6)
    - [Printed Material: General], 2008 (Box 99, Folder 7)
    - [Printed Material: General], 2008 (Box 100, Folder 1)
    - [Printed Material: General], 2008 (Box 100, Folder 2)
    - What's On Your Plate? - A Film by Catherine Gund, 2008 (Box 100, Folder 3)
    - Alaska Seafood Information Packet, 2008 (Box 100, Folder 4)
    - [Printed Material: General], 2008; [undated] (Box 100, Folder 5)
    - Bark Magazine, 2008 (Box 100, Folder 6)
    - [Menus], 2008-2012 (Box 100, Folder 7)
    - [Printed Material: General], 2009; [undated] (Box 101, Folder 1)
    - [Printed Material: General], 2009 (Box 101, Folder 2)
    - Bark Magazine, July/August 2009 (Box 101, Folder 3)
    - Bark Magazine, July/August 2009; February/March 2010 (Box 101, Folder 4)
    - [Printed Material: General], 2010; [undated] (Box 101, Folder 5)
    - [Printed Material: General], 2010; [undated] (Box 101, Folder 6)
    - [Printed Material: General], 2010-2012 (Box 101, Folder 7)
    - Center for Veterinary Medicine, 2011 (Box 101, Folder 8)
    - [Printed Material: General], 2011 (Box 102, Folder 1)
    - [Printed Material: General], 2012-2013 (Box 102, Folder 2)
    - Eating For Pleasure, Eating For Health: French and American Perspectives on Teaching About Food Conference, 2012 (Box 102, Folder 3)
    - [Printed Material: General], 2012 (Box 102, Folder 4)
    - [Printed Material: General], 2012; [undated] (Box 102, Folder 5)
    - The Welsh Rabbit Rabbit by Thomas J. Murray, [undated] (Box 102, Folder 6)
    - Kitchen Pinters From a Professional, [undated] (Box 102, Folder 7)
    - Ontario Greenhouse Gourmet, [undated] (Box 102, Folder 8)
- Series XI: Media
  Material has been arranged into two subseries comprising of video and audio.
  Series XI: Media is comprised of video and audio materials featuring Marion Nestle or relating to food studies.
  - Subseries A: Video
    Material is separated into VHS tapes and DVDs and arranged alphabetically.
    Conditions Governing Access
    Video materials have not been preserved and may not be available to researchers.
    - Over Easy IV Marion Nestle Segments, [1980]; ID: 159.0001 (Box 103, Media ID: 159.0001)
      DVD Access Copy Available
      Existence and Location of Copies
      Digibeta Preservation Master. DVD submaster.
      Physical Characteristics and Technical Requirements
      Original format: Betamax.
      Duration: 00:35:00
    - 1991 Selected Dance Works Created and Performed by Richard Allen and Karen Pearlman, 1987-1991; ID: 159.0002 (Box 103, Media ID: 159.0002)
      Original format: VHS.
      Currently unavailable.
    - Anderson Cooper 360 (1 Segment), December 6, 2004; ID: 159.0003 (Box 103, Media ID: 159.0003)
    - Center for Science in the Public Interest: Message from Dr. Michael F. Jacobson and News Clips in 2000, ID: 159.0004 (Box 103, Media ID: 159.0004)
    - Dateline/Cave Man Diet, May 24, 1999; ID: 159.0005 (Box 103, Media ID: 159.0005)
      Duration: 11 minutes.
    - Deconstructing Supper, 2002; ID: 159.0006 (Box 103, Media ID: 159.0006)
      Duration: 00:47:30
    - Dilated Pupils: Food Politics, undated; ID: 159.0007 (Box 103, Media ID: 159.0007)
    - Fields of Promise, 1995; ID: 159.0008 (Box 103, Media ID: 159.0008)
      Duration: 00:27:00
    - Food News & Views, November 22, 1993; ID: 159.0009 (Box 103, Media ID: 159.0009)
      Duration: 60 minutes.
    - Food Safety: Steak Houses, May 5, 2003; ID: 159.0010 (Box 103, Media ID: 159.0010)
    - Food Safety: Warehouse Clubs, April 28, 2003; ID: 159.0011 (Box 103, Media ID: 159.0011)
    - Fox News Red Bull Mixer dub, undated; ID: 159.0012 (Box 103, Media ID: 159.0012)
    - Frontline: Diet Wars, April 8, 2004; ID: 159.0013 (Box 103, Media ID: 159.0013)
    - Graham Kerr's Gathering Place: Episode 119, February 22, 2000; ID: 159.0014 (Box 103, Media ID: 159.0014)
      Duration: 00:58:33
    - The Ironic Politics of Obesity: A Food Systems Approach, September 20, 2003; ID: 159.0015 (Box 103, Media ID: 159.0015)
      Duration: 00:53:00
    - Junk Food Vending Machines in NYC Schools: Marion Nestle Interview Fox News at 10, April 22, 1999; ID: 159.0016 (Box 103, Media ID: 159.0016)
      Duration: 00:02:00
    - Kraft Foods--Healthy Eating Campaign: Marion Nestle of NYU Interviews ABC, CBS, CNN, MSNBC, NBC, July 1, 2003; ID: 159.0017 (Box 103, Media ID: 159.0017)
      Duration: 24 minutes.
    - Marion Nestle Martinson Lecture, University of Minnesota, September 17, 2004; ID: 159.0018 (Box 103, Media ID: 159.0018)
    - Marion Nestle: Reel, undated; ID: 159.0019 (Box 103, Media ID: 159.0019)
    - Marion Nestle Television Appearances, April 18, 2003-September 30, 2005; ID: 159.0020 (Box 103, Media ID: 159.0020)
      Duration: 47 minutes.
    - Massachusetts School of Law: Books of Our Time - Food Politics: How the Food Industry Influences Nutrition and Health, undated; ID: 159.0021 (Box 103, Media ID: 159.0021)
      Duration: 01:00:00
    - Mediterranean Update: Focus on Family, February 26, 1998; ID: 159.0022 (Box 103, Media ID: 159.0022)
      Duration: 00:17:00
    - Michael Shnayerson: Now with Bill Moyers & 60 Minutes, undated; ID: 159.0023 (Box 103, Media ID: 159.0023)
    - Modern Cuisine, February 27, 1993; March 17, 1993; ID: 159.0024 (Box 103, Media ID: 159.0024)
      Duration: 00:05:00
    - MSL Books of Our Time: Food Politics, September 8, 2005; ID: 159.0025 (Box 103, Media ID: 159.0025)
    - NBC Nightline: Jamie Oliver, Gene Grabowski, & Marion Nestle, September 30, 2005; ID: 159.0026 (Box 103, Media ID: 159.0026)
    - Nutrition: Ch. 9 Local, CBS News, MacNeil-Lehrer; ABC News; NBC News; GMA, ABC; CBS, July 28, 1988; undated; ID: 159.0027 (Box 103, Media ID: 159.0027)
    - Nutrition Friendly Schools, October 11, 2001; ID: 159.0028 (Box 103, Media ID: 159.0028)
      Duration: 00:11:00
    - O'Reilly Factor, December 2003; ID: 159.0029 (Box 103, Media ID: 159.0029)
    - Obesity in America, Peter Jennings, December 8, 2003; ID: 159.0030 (Box 104, Media ID: 159.0030)
    - On the Issues - Massaging the Media PBS Kringle Farms, April 22, 1994; ID: 159.0031 (Box 104, Media ID: 159.0031)
    - Orange Juice/Cancer, undated; ID: 159.0032 (Box 104, Media ID: 159.0032)
    - Organics: CBS News Sunday Morning, August 1, 2004; ID: 159.0033 (Box 104, Media ID: 159.0033)
    - PANORAMA: The Trouble with Sugar, October 10, 2004; ID: 159.0034 (Box 104, Media ID: 159.0034)
    - Papillon Hawaiian Helicopters "Tour Aerials", undated; ID: 159.0035 (Box 104, Media ID: 159.0035)
    - Parenting in the 90s: Eating Right segment CNBC, December 11-12, 1993; ID: 159.0036 (Box 104, Media ID: 159.0036)
    - Paula Zahn Now CNN, December 6, 2004; ID: 159.0037 (Box 104, Media ID: 159.0037)
    - Peter Jennings Reporting: How to Get Fat Without Really Trying, December 8, 2003; ID: 159.0038 (Box 104, Media ID: 159.0038)
    - Peter Jennings Reporting: How to Get Fat Without Really Trying, December 8, 2003; ID: 159.0039 (Box 104, Media ID: 159.0039)
      Original Format: VHS.
    - Peter Jennings Reporting: How to Get Fat Without Really Trying, December 8, 2003; ID: 159.0040 (Box 104, Media ID: 159.0040)
    - Prime Time Live: "Fat Chance", October 28, 1993; ID: 159.0041 (Box 104, Media ID: 159.0041)
    - Public Policy Institute-Speakers Series: Marion Nestle PhD MPH "Food Biotechnology & the Consumer", April 23, 1997; ID: 159.0042 (Box 104, Media ID: 159.0042)
    - Seeds of Innovation: Seeing Tomorrow's Harvest, undated; ID: 159.0043 (Box 104, Media ID: 159.0043)
    - Segment on Functional Foods - Marion Nestle of NYU - This Morning, July 9, 1999; ID: 159.0044 (Box 104, Media ID: 159.0044)
      Duration: 00:04:45
    - Soft Drinks in Schools: Exploring the Issues Part I, undated; ID: 159.0045 (Box 104, Media ID: 159.0045)
    - Soft Drinks in Schools: Exploring the Issues Part II, undated; ID: 159.0046 (Box 104, Media ID: 159.0046)
    - Studio 4 Episode #414 Marion Nestle, October 14, 2003; ID: 159.0047 (Box 104, Media ID: 159.0047)
      Duration: 00:57:30
    - "Super Size Me" EPK, undated; ID: 159.0048 (Box 104, Media ID: 159.0048)
      Duration: 00:06:37
    - VegSource 2002 Conference -- Tape 1 Dean Ornish MD, ID: 159.0049 (Box 104, Media ID: 159.0049)
      Duration: 01:34:00
    - VegSource 2002 Conference -- Tape 2 William Castelli MD, Michael Klaper MD, ID: 159.0050 (Box 104, Media ID: 159.0050)
      Duration: 02:00:00
    - VegSource 2003 Conference -- Tape 3 Marion Nestle PhD, T. Colin Campbell PhD, 2002; ID: 159.0051 (Box 104, Media ID: 159.0051)
    - VegSource 2002 Conference -- Tape 4 Caldwell Esselstyn MD, John & Ocean Robbins, Frances & Anna Lappé, ID: 159.0052 (Box 104, Media ID: 159.0052)
    - VegSource 2002 Conference -- Tape 5 John & Ocean Robbins, Frances & Anna Lappé (part 2), ID: 159.0053 (Box 104, Media ID: 159.0053)
    - VegSource 2002 Conference -- Tape 6 John McDougall MD, Representative Dennis Kucinich, ID: 159.0054 (Box 104, Media ID: 159.0054)
    - Vicki Gabereau Show Ep. #7-048, undated; ID: 159.0055 (Box 104, Media ID: 159.0055)
    - What to Eat? The Politics of Healthy Diets, undated; ID: 159.0056 (Box 104, Media ID: 159.0056)
    - WEB MD: [IV]: Dr. Corn, October 12, 2006; ID: 159.0057 (Box 104, Media ID: 159.0057)
      Empty VHS case.
    - [Unknown Tape], January 11, 2011; ID: 159.0058 (Box 104, Media ID: 159.0058)
    - [Unknown Tape], May 14, 2006; ID: 159.0059 (Box 104, Media ID: 159.0059)
    - 13th Annual Chef Culinary Conference, 2007; ID: 159.0136 (Box 105, Media ID: 159.0136)
      Original format: DVD.
    - Big Bucks Big Pharma: Marketing Disease & Pushing Drugs, circa 2006; ID: 159.0060 (Box 105, Media ID: 159.0060)
      Duration: 00:46:00
    - The Big Guy: Tom Delay's Stolen Congress, 2006; ID: 159.0061 (Box 105, Media ID: 159.0061)
      Duration: 01:17:00
    - The Botony of Desire, February 23, 2009; ID: 159.0062 (Box 105, Media ID: 159.0062)
    - The Brave New Films Boxset Bonus DVD, 2006; ID: 159.0063 (Box 105, Media ID: 159.0063)
    - Captive Audience: Advertising Invades the Classroom, 2003; ID: 159.0064 (Box 105, Media ID: 159.0064)
      Duration: 00:45:00
    - The Carroll F. Dooley Lecture Series: Dr. Marion Nestle "Food Politics: Chefs in the Middle", December 4, 2008; ID: 159.0075 (Box 105, Media ID: 159.0075)
      Duration: 01:30:24
    - Castor & Pollux Press Kit, circa February 2008; ID: 159.0065 (Box 105, Media ID: 159.0065)
    - CIES 53rd World Food Business Summit, June 17-19, 2009; ID: 159.0066 (Box 105, Media ID: 159.0066)
    - CIES 53rd World Food Business Summit "A Taste of Innovation: Ingredients For Success In US Food Retailing", June 17-19, 2009; ID: 159.0067 (Box 105, Media ID: 159.0067)
    - Common Ground Lobby Talks: "A Conversation with Marion Nestle", April 1, 2009; ID: 159.0068 (Box 105, Media ID: 159.0068)
    - The Culinary Vegetable Institute, undated; ID: 159.0069 (Box 105, Media ID: 159.0069)
    - Dogmatic: Wowbbler Dog, Wowbbler Kitty, Lasso, undated; ID: 159.0070 (Box 105, Media ID: 159.0070)
    - DOP Italia USA, April 7, 2008; ID: 159.0071 (Box 105, Media ID: 159.0071)
    - Eating Alaska, March 10, 2008; ID: 159.0072 (Box 105, Media ID: 159.0072)
      Duration: 01:02:00
    - Food Fight: A Story of Culinary Revolt Promo Trailer, undated; ID: 159.0073 (Box 105, Media ID: 159.0073)
    - Food Fight: A Story of Culinary Revolt Film Excerpt, undated; ID: 159.0074 (Box 105, Media ID: 159.0074)
      Duration: 00:08:00
    - Food Politics: Personal vs. Social Responsibility for Dietary Choices with Marion Nestle, March 24, 2010; ID: 159.0133 (Box 105, Media ID: 159.0133)
    - Global Exchange: Resisting Injustice, Creating Alternatives and Taking Action, 2009; ID: 159.0076 (Box 105, Media ID: 159.0076)
    - Harmony of Colors, 2007; ID: 159.0077 (Box 105, Media ID: 159.0077)
    - Hidden Kitchens: Texas, undated; ID: 159.0078 (Box 105, Media ID: 159.0078)
    - Hunger and Poverty in America 1968 and 2008, June 11, 2008; ID: 159.0079 (Box 105, Media ID: 159.0079)
    - Iraq for Sale: The War of Profiteers, 2006; ID: 159.0080 (Box 105, Media ID: 159.0080)
      Duration: 01:30:00
    - "Just Grapes" Version 2 by Jonathan Russo, undated; ID: 159.0081 (Box 105, Media ID: 159.0081)
    - Laughing Liberally '06: Saving Democracy One Laugh at a Time, 2007; ID: 159.0082 (Box 105, Media ID: 159.0082)
    - Luchemos Contra la Promócion de Alimentos Chatarra entre los Niños, 2006; ID: 159.0083 (Box 105, Media ID: 159.0083)
      Duration: 00:14:30
    - Lunch Lessons & Bringing Ideas to the Table, undated; ID: 159.0084 (Box 105, Media ID: 159.0084)
    - Lunch Lessons: Changing the Way We Feed Our Children, undated; ID: 159.0085 (Box 105, Media ID: 159.0085)
    - Marion Nestle CNN Eatocracy, undated; ID: 159.0132 (Box 105, Media ID: 159.0132)
    - Media City: Center for Communication "The High Cost of Cheap Food", undated; ID: 159.0086 (Box 105, Media ID: 159.0086)
    - Natural Products Expo East: Keynote Marion Nestle, October 5, 2006; ID: 159.0087 (Box 105, Media ID: 159.0087)
    - NCQA The Future in Focus: Health Quality Award Winners 2005, ID: 159.0088 (Box 105, Media ID: 159.0088)
    - Studio 4 - Shaw TV: Marion Nestle, May 11, 2007; ID: 159.0089 (Box 105, Media ID: 159.0089)
    - NYU Faculty Interview: Marion Nestle, October 2007; ID: 159.0090 (Box 105, Media ID: 159.0090)
    - Ontario Outlook Conference 2008, ID: 159.0091 (Box 105, Media ID: 159.0091)
    - Pet Food: A Dog's Breakfast, undated; ID: 159.0092 (Box 105, Media ID: 159.0092)
      Duration: 00:42:18
    - Penn & Teller: Bullshit! "Ground Zero", undated; ID: 159.0093 (Box 105, Media ID: 159.0093)
    - Penn & Teller: Bullshit! "Sleep, Inc.", undated; ID: 159.0094 (Box 105, Media ID: 159.0094)
    - Penn & Teller: Bullshit! "Video Games", undated; 159.0095 (Box 105, Media 159.0095)
    - Premium Nutrition in a Shape Dogs Love, undated; 159.0096 (Box 105, Media 159.0096)
    - Processed People: The Documentary, 2009; ID: 159.0097 (Box 105, Media ID: 159.0097)
      Duration: 00:40:00
    - Public Affairs: Slow Food Long Version, July 23, 2007; ID: 159.0098 (Box 105, Media ID: 159.0098)
      Duration: 00:13:42
    - Seafood Watch Training Program: Training DVD Disc 1, 2007; ID: 159.0099 (Box 105, Media ID: 159.0099)
    - Seafood Watch Training Program: Training Film Disc 2, 2007; ID: 159.0100 (Box 105, Media ID: 159.0100)
    - The UCSF Medalists 2006, ID: 159.0101 (Box 105, Media ID: 159.0101)
    - "We need better school food!", 2009; 159.0102 (Box 105, Media 159.0102)
      Duration: 00:03:00
    - "We need better school food!", 2009; 159.0103 (Box 105, Media 159.0103)
    - What's On Your Plate?: trailer, undated; 159.0104 (Box 105, Media 159.0104)
      Duration: 00:11:30
    - What to Eat: Personal Responsibility vs. Social Responsibility - Marion Nestle in Conversation with Chef Bobo, February 28, 2008; ID: 159.0105 (Box 105, Media ID: 159.0105)
    - World Nutrition Rio 2012, April 27-30, 2012; 159.0106 (Box 105, Media 159.0106)
    - A World of Possibilities - Oversized and Undernourished: The Expanding Epidemic of Childhood Obesity, 2006; ID: 159.0107 (Box 105, Media ID: 159.0107)
  - Subseries B: Audio
    Material is separated into casette tapes and CDs and arranged alphabetically.
    Audio materials have not been preserved and may not be available to researchers.